Jesus says in Matthew 12:40
For as Jonas was three days and three nights in the whale's belly; so shall the Son of man be three days and three nights in the heart of the earth.
Jonah 2
Now the LORD had prepared a great fish to swallow up Jonah. And Jonah was in the belly of the fish three days and three nights.
Then Jonah prayed unto the LORD his God out of the fish's belly,
And said, I cried by reason of mine affliction unto the LORD, and he heard me; out of the belly of hell cried I, and thou heardest my voice.
For thou hadst cast me into the deep, in the midst of the seas; and the floods compassed me about: all thy billows and thy waves passed over me.
Then I said, I am cast out of thy sight; yet I will look again toward thy holy temple.
The waters compassed me about, even to the soul: the depth closed me round about, the weeds were wrapped about my head.
I went down to the bottoms of the mountains; the earth with her bars was about me for ever: yet hast thou brought up my life from corruption, O LORD my God.
When my soul fainted within me I remembered the LORD: and my prayer came in unto thee, into thine holy temple.
They that observe lying vanities forsake their own mercy.
But I will sacrifice unto thee with the voice of thanksgiving; I will pay that that I have vowed. Salvation is of the LORD.
And the LORD spake unto the fish, and it vomited out Jonah upon the dry land.
Jonah's three days and three nights are thus clearly connected to the crucifixion of Christ.
Does the sign of the prophet Jonas have anything to do with us?
Christ bruised the serpent's head.
He had to die because Adam and Eve deliberately violated God’s explicit prohibition:
Of every tree of the garden thou mayest freely eat: But of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, thou shalt not eat of it: for in the day that thou eatest thereof thou shalt surely die.
And because of that Christ had to die.
After all, God had made a promise about it right after the Fall.
When He had first spoken to Adam and Eve, He said this to the serpent:
And I will put enmity between thee and the woman, and between thy seed and her seed;
it shall bruise thy head, and thou shalt bruise his heel.
That bruising took place on the cross.
In it sin and death lost all power,
the devil, in fact, already lost all power.
Christ has the power and omnipotence because what happened on the cross.
And while in this world many things seem to be much different,
that too is mostly what God allows the devil to rage.
The sign of the prophet Jonas and the crucifixion of Christ and the three days in the tomb belong together,
but so also the death of Christ belongs to us.
Namely, in the sixth chapter of Romans, Paul writes:
Know ye not, that so many of us as were baptized into Jesus Christ were baptized into his death?
Therefore if you have been baptized in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit,
then you have been baptized into the death of Christ. You have already died in that same death.
Therefore we are buried with him by baptism into death:
that like as Christ was raised up from the dead by the glory of the Father,
even so we also should walk in newness of life.
Baptism invites you to live in daily repentance.
The old is dead and the new must be arise together with Christ.
We have been baptized into Christ, together with Christ we will be resurrected.
For if we have been planted together in the likeness of his death,
we shall be also in the likeness of his resurrection: